Lori E. Schafer

592 Salisbury Street Worcester MA 01609 774.345.0838 schafer99@gmail.com

Communications Professional Possesses Abundant Passion, Experience, and Talent

"From branding and promoting our unique client advisory approach, to managing the positioning and storytelling of our multi-million dollar corporate expansion project, to launching and promoting our new philanthropic venture, Lori Schafer has been there for us in every way imaginable. This has been a very successful working relationship."

Edward F. Manzi, Jr., President & CEO, Fidelity Bank

Summary of Qualifications

PR expertise with nonprofits & private sector Exceptional creative talents
Communications program creation & supervision Highly skilled networker, collaborator & strategist Extensive PR connections w/i community

Excellent client testimonials

Demonstrated talent & enthusiasm for storytelling

Proven ability to maximize relationships

Relish public appearances

Utilize facebook & blogs

Professional Experience

Lori Schafer Public Relations, Worcester MA

2010 – present

Owner/Director

Public Relations Consulting Service

- Diverse regional clients simultaneously managed
- Media campaigns for new products or initiatives a particular strength
- Tapped for public event conception and execution
- Successfully turned crises into PR opportunities

On Target Communications, Worcester MA

2008 - 2009

Co-Founder and Managing Partner

Public Relations Firm

- Women-owned partnership with 20 diverse client projects in first year
- Higher Ed, healthcare, banking, arts & entertainment, and nonprofit clients
- Our work resulted in client initiatives and products attaining national media attention
- Managed team of designers, writers and others on multiple projects
- Produced web sites, collateral, and Internet/traditional media campaigns
- Improved each client's image and helped magnify their brand

Davis Advertising, Worcester MA

2002 - 2008

Public Relations Director

Advertising Agency

- Initiated and independently ran agency's Public Relations department
- Created LifeDesign(sm) for Fidelity Bank in 2003, their core branding tool
- One-on-one coaching and personalized messaging for CEOs
- Developed new philanthropic projects and other "cause marketing" initiatives for clients

Managing Director/Account Executive

Company was idea generator/problem solver that served more than 40 agencies and clients, both here and abroad. Main premise was to "crack the code" for those problems when agencies could not find solutions that satisfied clients. Company was owned and operated by Jeff Wolff (my husband), a highly regarded, much sought-after creative talent for two decades. I accompanied him to all initial meetings, and participated in extensive Q & A. From that point on, I served as the account manager, a liaison between Jeff and the clients. Additionally, I worked with freelance photographers, illustrators, and other creatives when they were brought in on projects. These years working with The Thought Process laid the groundwork for all that followed.

Furthermore, Hudson NY

1994 - 1996

Program Manager

Grant-making Program of the J. M. Kaplan Fund

- Developed, launched, and operated new arm of a notable private family foundation
- Nurtured program growth from a few dozen to hundreds of grantees annually (printed matter focus)
- Managed all office and financial operations and served as project's PR spokesperson

Various NYC museums, galleries, and arts organizations

1986 - 1993

Museum Professional

Solomon R. Guggenheim Museum, Museum of Modern Art, Andy Warhol Foundation, The Jewish Museum, several major private collectors, and internationally recognized artists

- All employers received my extensive knowledge of the art world and art history
- Demonstrated discretion and detailed approach in service of high-value collections
- Developed and managed special exhibitions, provided for secure transport, and collaborated with international entities; traveled extensively to safeguard cargo

Community Service

Member,	Board o	f Directors	and Advisor	v Board

2002 - Present

Rainbow Child Development Center, Inc., Worcester MA

Member, Board of Directors

Worcester Animal Rescue League, Worcester MA

2010 - Present

Communications Consultant

2006 - Present

Center for Nonviolent Solutions, Worcester MA

Northeast Organic Farming Association, MA Chapter (NOFA/Mass), Barre MA

Many Hands Organic Farm & Sustainability Center, Barre MA

Sheep to Shawl, Llama to Pajama 2010, Worcester MA (City of Worcester Green Hill Park Farm)

Education

St. Lawrence University, Canton NY City University of New York Graduate Center, NYC BA Cum Laude, German & Fine Art Graduate Program in Art History